Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/rhimanshu (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Cloud Computing
Amazon Web Services (AWS)
Python

Languages

Marathi (Limited Working) English (Full Professional) Hindi (Native or Bilingual)

Certifications

Machine Learning

AMCAT Certified Data Processing Specialist

Getting Started with Google Kubernetes Engine

Oracle Cloud Infrastructure 2018 Certified Architect Associate

"Python for Data Science and Machine Learning Bootcamp"

Honors-Awards

"Certificate Of Appreciation"
PyTorch Summer Hackathon Menlo
Park 2019

Himanshu Raj

Data Scientist at TensorIoT Inc.

Fullerton, California

Summary

Master's degree in Computer Science with concentration in Machine Learning and Data Science along with Cloud Technologies. I keep trying to have hands-on knowledge in GCP | AWS | Machine Learning | Computer Vision | Data Science.

I have a interest in recommendation systems, image processing, deep learning, cloud platforms and open-source technologies. I have a passion for data to apply insights and to solve business problems. I see myself as an excellent communicator and self-motivated professional with meticulous attention to detail.

Apart from academia, I have an industry experienced of more than 1.5 years with a solid understanding in Software Life Cycle, Software Design, Object Oriented Development, Coding, and Testing.

Technical Skills:

- Programming Language: Python, C, C++
- Frameworks: Hadoop (Map Reduce, Hive), Apache Spark, Flask
- Cloud Services: Amazon Web Service (AWS), Google Cloud Platform (GCP), Docker
- Libraries: TensorFlow, OpenCV, Numpy, Pandas, Keras
- Databases: MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB
- Web Technologies: RESTful web services, JSON, XML
- Tools: Docker, Kubernetes, Eclipse, Atom, Git, Jenkins, Postman, JIRA, Tableau, MS Office
- Methodologies: Agile, Scrum, Kanban, Test Driven Development (TDD), UML, Design Patterns
- Statistical Methods: Time Series, Hypothesis Testing, PCA, Factor Analysis, ANOVA, EDA, Correlation
- ML: NLP, Decision Trees, Neural Networks, SVM, Random Forest, Clustering, Boosting, Ensemble
- Operating Systems: Windows, Ubuntu, iOS

Experience

TensorIoT Inc.
Data Scientist
July 2019 - Present (9 months)

Sitch Ai 8 months

Al Engineering Intern August 2018 - December 2018 (5 months) Greater Los Angeles Area

- An emotional Ai application for POS consoles to identify customer's emotions.
- Implemented using Keras and convolutional neural network, used data augmentation.
- Maintained and configured user accounts for dev, QA and production servers and created roles for EC2, S3, CloudWatch

Deep Learning Intern
May 2018 - August 2018 (4 months)
Greater Los Angeles Area

- Designed and developed cutting-edge deep learning algorithms applicable to image data analysis, computer vision, NLP and OCR
- Designed an application to eliminate the manual entry of card classification by supervisors using Optical Character Recognition and Convolutional Neural Network.

OpenDev Technologies Pvt. Ltd Trainee April 2016 - March 2017 (1 year) Pune Area, India

- Created stored procedures using SQL to automate report generation for customers using batch process
- Collaborated with stakeholders to maintain database which includes data cleaning, preprocessing & transformation

Education

California State University, Fullerton

Master of Science - MS, Computer Science · (2017 - 2019)

University of Pune
Engineer's Degree, Computer Engineering